A Guide to the Papers of George William Child, 1847-1881
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of George William Child, 1847-1881
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6819-a
This collection consists of 15 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library [July 1972] October 24, 1979.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of letters, 1851-1881, bound in an extra-illustrated copy of Recollections which are to or from people mentioned in the book. These include letters from G.P.R. James on the consulate at Norfolk, Va., Hablot Knight Brown on graphotypes, Lytton Bulwer on a charitable request, William Howitt requesting Irish sketches from Carlton, and a patronage request from Simon Cameron to President Grant.
Also Charles Dickens on funeral arrangements, Samuel Randall and William T. Sherman conveying personal news, Ralph Waldo Emerson, Henry W. Longfellow and Fitz-Greene Halleck sending regrets, Matthew Arnold sending thanks, and George Bancroft sending checks.
The letters are tipped in George William Child's Recollections, J. B. Lippincott, 1890, in the Manuscripts Department, in the order in which they fall.
Contents List
- George Bancroft to R. Withers 1851 Aug 16, ALS, 1 p.
  Sends two checks ($500 and $351) to credit his account
- G[eorge]; P[ayne]; R[ainsford] James to Madam _____ 1853 Jul 31, ALS, 3 p.
  Discusses his labors in putting the consulate in Norfolk, Virginia into order
- Charles Dickens to _____ Mansell n.d., ALS, 1 p.
  Concerns arrangements for funeral of W. Fleming
- Henry Wadsworth Longfellow to "Dear Sir" 1877 Apr 19, ALS, 1 p.
  Has no material on subject requested
- Hablot Knight Browne to H. Ftizcocke n.d., ALS, 2 p.
  Prefers graphotype to woodcutting because it render artwork more faithfully
- R[obert?] Patterson to George William Childs 1881 Mar 17, ALS, 1 p.
  Recommends William N. Clifford as correspondent
- Samuel Randall to S. C. Lyford 1881 Dec 30, ALS, 1 p.
  Is at a New York hotel. Thanks for sending [Borup's?] letter. Will be glad to hear of S. C. L.'s travels
- William Tecumseh Sherman to ____ 1876 May 29, ALS, 3 p.
  Is glad to hear of correspondent's new job. Gives travel schedule; plans to attend son Tom's graduation exercises at Yale. Refers to desk which has not arrived.
- Ralph Waldo Emerson to [John] Bigelow 1857 Sep 24, ALS, 2 p.
  Cannot go to Cleveland; will try later in the season
- Lytton Bulwer to "Sir" n.d., ALS, 1 p.
  Asks correspondent to corroborate story of a cripple named Addison, and to give him money
- Matthew Arnold to "My dear Sir" 1875 Jan 10, ALS, 1 p.
  Regrets that he did not see Professor in Edinburg; thanks him for lectures on Turgot
- William Howitt to Richard Webb [1847] Mar 2, ALS, 4 p.
  Refers to Webb's letter to "William," and to the warfare between two journals. Would like some Irish sketches from Carlton
- Fitz-Greene Halleck to Homer V. Smith 1861 Jan 24, ALS, 2 p.
  Regrets he cannot honor request for "four lines" -- it is too long since he has attempted anything
- Charles Dickens sending regards to Mrs. [Annie Adams?] Fields on his calling card n.d., AN
- Simon Cameron to President [Ulysses Simpson] Grant 1876 Jun 26, ALS, 1 p.
  Recommends Mr. Leisinning's case objecting to being replaced by Turner Schley as postmaster of Charleston, West Virginia